Guide to The Women's Sports Foundation Records 1950-2019 (bulk, 1974-2018) MS 3199
New-York Historical Society
- Series V. Photographs, 1951-2008; 24 Linear feet in 24 record cartons
  - Subseries V.B. Events and staff, 1973-2007; 13.5 Linear feet in 13.5 record cartons
    - WSF property photos, 1991 (Offsite-box 248, Folder 76)
    - Advisory photos/meetings: Donna Lopiano, circa 1985-1995 (Offsite-box 248, Folder 77)
    - Advisory photos/ meetings: Advisory Board meetings, circa 1985-1995 (Offsite-box 248, Folder 78)
    - Aspire Higher, 1986 (Offsite-box 248, Folder 79)
    - Aspire Higher, 1988 (Offsite-box 248, Folder 80)
    - Aspire Higher announcement, circa 1985-1990 (Offsite-box 248, Folder 81)
    - BJK International Center, circa 1985-1990 (Offsite-box 248, Folder 82)
    - Challenge of Champions, 1987 (Offsite-box 248, Folder 83)
    - Challenge of Champions, 1988 (Offsite-box 248, Folder 84)
    - Geena Davis takes aim photo shoot (3 folders), 2001 (Offsite-box 248, Folder 85-87)
    - Clinics - Charlotte (4 folders), 1996-1999 (Offsite-box 249, Folder 1-4)
    - Coaches (2 folders), 1989-1997 (Offsite-box 249, Folder 5-6)
    - Coaches: Theresa Grentz, 1992 (Offsite-box 249, Folder 7)
    - Dare to Compete HBO, 1990 (Offsite-box 249, Folder 8)
    - Coor's Balancing Act: June Harrison, 1996 (Offsite-box 249, Folder 9)
    - Donna's speaking engagements: Advertising women of New York, circa 1980-2000 (Offsite-box 249, Folder 10)
    - Family fitness, circa 1980-2000 (Offsite-box 249, Folder 11)
    - Gillette Con. of Champions, 1973 (Offsite-box 249, Folder 12)
    - Gillette Con. of Champions, 1996 (Offsite-box 249, Folder 13)
    - Girl Scouts (3 folders), 1993-1997 (Offsite-box 249, Folder 14-16)
    - Coaches awards, 1990-1991 (Offsite-box 249, Folder 17)
    - Greatest American Woman Athlete of the last 25 Years, circa 1990 (Offsite-box 249, Folder 18)
    - Hall of Fame (3 folders), 1980-1999 (Offsite-box 249, Folder 19-21)
    - In a Class by themselves, 1982 (Offsite-box 249, Folder 22)
    - Lever stride Atlanta, 1988 (Offsite-box 249, Folder 23)
    - Male athletes, 1992 (Offsite-box 249, Folder 24)
    - Miller Lite Press Conference (2 folders), 1989 (Offsite-box 249, Folder 25-26)
    - Minority Report press conference, 1989 (Offsite-box 249, Folder 27)
    - New Agenda I, 1983 (Offsite-box 249, Folder 28)
    - New Agenda II, 1985 (Offsite-box 249, Folder 29)
    - New Jersey Stars, circa 1980-1995 (Offsite-box 249, Folder 30)
    - Olympics, 1994 (Offsite-box 249, Folder 31)
    - Prairie State Games, 1988 (Offsite-box 249, Folder 32)
    - Purpose of WSF slides, 1987-1988 (Offsite-box 249, Folder 33)
    - Reebok Sport Training Challenge, 1997 (Offsite-box 249, Folder 34)
    - Reebok/WSF Girls Sports Leadership Summit, 1997 (Offsite-box 249, Folder 35)
    - Run, Jane, Run!, 1984 (Offsite-box 249, Folder 36)
    - Sports and kids conference, 1999 (Offsite-box 249, Folder 37)
    - Sudafed Sports Fantasy Camps (2 folders), 1991-1992 (Offsite-box 249, Folder 38-39)
    - AAU Sullivan Awards Finalists, 1987 (Offsite-box 249, Folder 40)
    - Symphony of Sports, 1989 (Offsite-box 249, Folder 41)
    - Take your daughter to work day, circa 1985-1995 (Offsite-box 249, Folder 42)
    - Teen Pregnancy press conference (2 folders), 1998 May 13 (Offsite-box 249, Folder 43-44)
    - Title IX - Gender Equity, circa 1990 (Offsite-box 250, Folder 1)
    - Title IX at 30 (2 folders), 2002 (Offsite-box 250, Folder 2-3)
    - Up and Coming Winners, 1989-1992 (Offsite-box 250, Folder 4)
    - Virginia Slims Tournament, 1985-1989 (Offsite-box 250, Folder 5)
    - Women sport photographers, 1983-1995 (Offsite-box 250, Folder 6)
    - Women's sports leadership workshop, 1993-1997 (Offsite-box 250, Folder 7)
    - Women's sports medicine, circa 1990s (Offsite-box 250, Folder 8)
    - First World Conference on Women and Sport, 1996 (Offsite-box 250, Folder 9)
    - WSF booths, conferences, and seminars, 1989-1990 (Offsite-box 250, Folder 10)
    - Golf outing, 1997 (Offsite-box 250, Folder 10)
    - Danskin triathlon seminar, 1990 July 28 (Offsite-box 250, Folder 11)
    - Women's Global Challenge press conference, 1997 (Offsite-box 250, Folder 12)
    - [WSF booths at conferences/seminars], 1994 (Offsite-box 250, Folder 13)
    - Aim Higher, 2000 (Offsite-box 250, Folder 14)
    - When Billie Beat Bobby, 2001 (Offsite-box 250, Folder 15)
    - Photographer files and miscellaneous: agents, circa 1990 (Offsite-box 250, Folder 16)
    - Permanent WSF staff photos: Donna Lopiano, 1990 (Offsite-box 250, Folder 17)
    - Permanent WSF staff photos, 1990-1993 (Offsite-box 250, Folder 18)
    - Permanent WSF staff photos: Eva Auchincloss, circa 1985 (Offsite-box 250, Folder 19)
    - Permanent WSF staff photos: Sal Schiliro - Trustee, circa 1980-1990 (Offsite-box 250, Folder 20)
    - Permanent WSF staff photos: Gloria Steinem, 1987 (Offsite-box 250, Folder 21)
    - Permanent WSF staff photos: Kristine Clark-Setnes, 1994 (Offsite-box 250, Folder 22)
    - Permanent WSF staff photos: Holly Turner, 1973 (Offsite-box 250, Folder 23)
    - Permanent WSF staff photos: Donna Lopiano material, 2007 (Offsite-box 250, Folder 24)
    - Staff and interns (3 folders), 1987-2000 (Offsite-box 250, Folder 25-27)
    - Trustees, 1999 (Offsite-box 250, Folder 28)
    - Marj Snyder, 1990-1993 (Offsite-box 250, Folder 29)
    - [Interns], circa 1985-1995 (Offsite-box 250, Folder 30)
    - Philip Guarascio, circa 1985-1995 (Offsite-box 250, Folder 31)
    - Thomas Gulotta, circa 1985-1995 (Offsite-box 250, Folder 32)
    - Lannin House, circa 1985-1995 (Offsite-box 250, Folder 33)
    - NYAD NYC dinner, 1981 (Offsite-box 251, Folder 1)
    - NYAD, 1982 (Offsite-box 251, Folder 2)
    - NYC dinner, 1983 (Offsite-box 251, Folder 3)
    - NYC dinner (2 folders), 1984 (Offsite-box 251, Folder 4-5)
    - NYC dinner, 1985 (Offsite-box 251, Folder 6)
    - NYC dinner, 1986 (Offsite-box 251, Folder 7)
    - New York Awards Dinner, 1987 (Offsite-box 251, Folder 8)
    - New York dinner, 1988 (Offsite-box 251, Folder 9)
    - A Salute to Women in Sports, 1989 (Offsite-box 251, Folder 10)
    - Dinner kick-off party, 1989 (Offsite-box 251, Folder 11)
    - Dinner kick-off party, 1990 September 11 (Offsite-box 251, Folder 12)
    - NYAD dinner, 1991 (Offsite-box 251, Folder 13)
    - [NYAD], 1992 (Offsite-box 251, Folder 14)
    - [NYAD] (3 folders), 1993 (Offsite-box 251, Folder 15-17)
    - [NYAD] (3 folders), 1994 (Offsite-box 251, Folder 18-20)
    - New York Awards Dinner (3 folders), 1995 (Offsite-box 252, Folder 1-3)
    - NYAD, 1996 (Offsite-box 252, Folder 4)
    - NYAD, 1997 (Offsite-box 252, Folder 5)
    - NYAD, 1998 (Offsite-box 252, Folder 6)
    - NYAD, 1999 (Offsite-box 252, Folder 7)
    - NYAD, 2000 (Offsite-box 252, Folder 8)
    - NYAD, 2001 (Offsite-box 252, Folder 9)
    - NYAD, 2002 (Offsite-box 252, Folder 10)
    - NGWSD (13 folders), 1987-1996 (Offsite-box 252, Folder 11-23)
    - NGWSD (2 folders), 1997-1998 (Offsite-box 253, Folder 1-2)
    - Summit, 1996 (Offsite-box 253, Folder 3)
    - [Events], 1997 (Offsite-box 253, Folder 4)
    - NGWSD, 1997 (Offsite-box 253, Folder 5)
    - Summit, 1998 (Offsite-box 253, Folder 6)
    - Summit, 1999 (Offsite-box 253, Folder 7)
    - Summit, 2000 (Offsite-box 253, Folder 8)
    - Summit, 2001 (Offsite-box 253, Folder 9)
    - NGWSD, 1993 (Offsite-box 253, Folder 10)
    - Summit Orlando Florida (5 folders), 1996 (Offsite-box 253, Folder 11-15)
    - NGWSD (3 folders), 1999 (Offsite-box 253, Folder 16-18)
    - Summit, 1991 (Offsite-box 253, Folder 19)
    - Summit, 1996 (Offsite-box 253, Folder 20)
    - [Events] (2 folders), circa 1990-1999 (Offsite-box 253, Folder 21-22)
    - Summit [binder], 1998 (Offsite-box 259, Item 1)
    - NGWSD [binder], 1998 (Offsite-box 259, Item 2)
    - NYAD photos June Harrison Gale Griffiths [binder], 1998 (Offsite-box 259, Item 3)
    - NYAD photos Gina Gayle Nancy Ploeger Carol Foell Gayle Burns [binder], 1998 (Offsite-box 259, Item 4)
    - Dinner photos and negatives [binder], 1999 (Offsite-box 259, Item 5)
    - Dinner negatives [binder], 2000 (Offsite-box 259, Item 6)
    - NYAD [binder], 2000 (Offsite-box 260, Item 1)
    - NYAD [binder], 2002 (Offsite-box 260, Item 2)
    - NYAD print photos [binder], 2003 (Offsite-box 260, Item 3)
    - No Limits Awards Dinner [binder], 2000 (Offsite-box 261, Item 1)
    - Summit [binder], 2001 (Offsite-box 261, Item 2)
    - NYAD [binder], 2001 (Offsite-box 261, Item 3)
    - NGWSD [binder], 2002 (Offsite-box 261, Item 4)
    - NGWSD photos [binder], 2003 (Offsite-box 261, Item 5)
    - New York Dinner and New York Dinner Press Conference with Ferraro [binder], 1984 (Offsite-box 263, Item 1)
    - New York Dinners [binder], 1986-1987 (Offsite-box 263, Item 2)
    - New York Dinner and Press Conference [binder], 1985 (Offsite-box 263, Item 3)
    - Washington D.C. awards program and San Francisco awards program [binder], 1985 (Offsite-box 263, Item 4)
    - A Salute to Women in Sports [binder], 1989 (Offsite-box 263, Item 5)
    - New York Dinner [binder], 1989 (Offsite-box 263, Item 6)
    - A Salute to Women in Sports [binder], 1990 (Offsite-box 263, Item 7)
    - New York dinner [binder], 1992 (Offsite-box 267, Item 1)
    - NYAD [binder], 1991 (Offsite-box 267, Item 2)
    - Awards dinner- Billie Jean King, Elton John, and award winners [3 framed photographs], circa 2005 (Offsite-box 267, Item 3-5)
    - Press photographs, circa 1980-1995 (Offsite-box 267, Folder 1)
    - 21st Annual Salute to Women in Sports Awards Dinner, 2000 (Offsite-box 268, Folder 1)
    - New Agenda slides, 1983 (Offsite-box 268, Folder 2)
    - The Billies, 2008 (Offsite-box 268, Folder 3)
    - NGWSD, 2003 (Offsite-box 268, Folder 4)
    - [Events], circa 2000-2008 (Offsite-box 268, Folder 5)
    - The Billies, 2006 (Offsite-box 268, Folder 6)
    - Annual Salute to Women in Sports Awards Dinner, 2002 (Offsite-box 268, Folder 7)
    - Scholar Sportswoman of the Year awards, 2006 (Offsite-box 268, Folder 8)
    - NYAD, 1999 (Offsite-box 268, Folder 9)
    - [Events], circa 2006 (Offsite-box 268, Folder 10)
    - Sporting Woman, 1998 (Offsite-box 268, Folder 11)
    - Donna Lopiano (2 folders), circa 1990-2008 (Offsite-box 268, Folder 12-13)
    - Dr. Beverly Stunden, circa 1970s-1980s (Offsite-box 268, Folder 14)
    - Publicity slides, circa 1980-1990 (Offsite-box 268, Folder 15)
    - [Event negatives] (2 folders), circa 1990-2005 (Offsite-box 268, Folder 16-17)
    - Bob Hope's Cavalcade of Sports portraits, 1973 (Offsite-box 268, Folder 18)
    - Female Athlete Triad slides [3 binders], circa 1990 (Offsite-box 269, Item 1-3)
    - Publicity and promotion slides [binder], 1989 (Offsite-box 269, Item 4)
    - Annual Conference [binder], 1992 (Offsite-box 269, Item 5)
    - A Salute to Women in Sports [binder], circa 1980-1990 (Offsite-box 269, Item 6)
    - Minority Report slides [binder], 1989 August 15 (Offsite-box 270, Item 1)
    - New Agenda Conference and New Agenda Conference II slides [binder], 1983-1987 (Offsite-box 270, Item 2)
    - Pest control locker room album, circa 1995 (Offsite-box 270, Item 3)
    - "Misc. WSF slides" box, circa 1980-1995 (Offsite-box 270, Item 4)
    - Geena Davis autographed photographs, circa 1995-2005 (Offsite-box 270, Folder 1)
    - Lisa Leslie NGWSD autographed photograph, circa 1995-2005 (Offsite-box 270, Folder 2)
    - NGWSD proclamation signings and ceremonies, 1987-1988 (Offsite-box 270, Folder 3)
    - Web photo info (Offsite-box 270, Folder 4)
    - [Events], circa 1995-2007 (Offsite-box 270, Folder 5)
    - [Mailed photos received by WSF] (3 folders), circa 1990-2005 (Offsite-box 270, Folder 6-8)
  - Subseries V.C. Sports alphabetical file, circa 1980-2005; 2 Linear feet in 2 record cartons
    Suberies V.C contains an alphabetical file of photographs organized by sport name. The alphabetical files are followed by a group of additional folders containing youth sports photographs and additional subjects. Formats include photographs and slides. Material is largely undated, but circa 1980-2000.
    The files are arranged in order as received from the donor. A run of files in alphabetical order by sport is followed by a group of additional folders containing youth sports photographs and additional subjects.
    - Sports alphabetical file: A-Basketball (4 folders), circa 1980-2005 (Offsite-box 253, Folder 23-26)
    - Sports alphabetical file: Basketball-R (39 folders), circa 1980-2005 (Offsite-box 254, Folder 1-39)
    - Sports alphabetical file: R-Y (19 folders), circa 1980-2005 (Offsite-box 255, Folder 1-19)
    - Hall of Fame, circa 1980-2005 (Offsite-box 255, Folder 20)
    - Basketball [youth], circa 1990-2005 (Offsite-box 255, Folder 21)
    - Football [youth], circa 1990-2005 (Offsite-box 255, Folder 22)
    - Soccer [youth], circa 1990-2005 (Offsite-box 255, Folder 23)
    - Softball [youth], circa 1990-2005 (Offsite-box 255, Folder 24)
    - Girls' track, circa 1990-2005 (Offsite-box 255, Folder 25)
    - Girls' sports photos, circa 1990-2005 (Offsite-box 255, Folder 26)
    - Girls' summer sports (2 folders), circa 1990-2005 (Offsite-box 255, Folder 27-28)
    - Girls' winter sports, circa 1990-2005 (Offsite-box 255, Folder 29)
  - Subseries V.D. Slide carousels, circa 1980-1995; 4 Linear feet in 4 record cartons
    Subseries V.D contains boxed slide carousel trays, slides, and presentation materials created and used by the WSF. The carousels are labelled by presentation or event title and have been retained in their original boxes. The title of each item has been transcribed from the box. Presentation materials include a variety of formats, including the slides, printed presentation scripts and notes, and audio cassettes, and varies for each presentation. Presentations date circa 1980-1995.
    Materials are arranged by order of receipt from the donor.
    - Sport for Everybody sync show and tape, circa 1980-1995 (Offsite-box 256, Box 1)
    - Women's Slide show, circa 1980-1995 (Offsite-box 256, Box 2)
    - Fit for Life Women's show slides, cassette, script, circa 1980-1995 (Offsite-box 256, Box 3)
    - Mixed Audience copy 1, circa 1980-1995 (Offsite-box 256, Box 4)
    - [Untitled], circa 1980-1995 (Offsite-box 256, Box 5)
    - Girls' show copy 2, circa 1980-1995 (Offsite-box 257, Box 1)
    - Girls' show copy 3, circa 1980-1995 (Offsite-box 257, Box 2)
    - Men's show copy 1, circa 1980-1995 (Offsite-box 257, Box 3)
    - Men's show copy 2, circa 1980-1995 (Offsite-box 257, Box 4)
    - New Horizons copy 2, circa 1980-1995 (Offsite-box 257, Box 5)
    - New Horizons, circa 1980-1995 (Offsite-box 258, Box 1)
    - Presentation at Trustee meeting of the WSF programs, 1990 October 14 (Offsite-box 262, Box 1)
    - Dinner, 1990 (Offsite-box 262, Box 2)
    - Images & Words slide presentation, circa 1980-1995 (Offsite-box 262, Item 3)
- Series VI. womenSports magazine [RESTRICTED/ unprocessed], 1974-2000; 39 Linear feet in 39 record cartons
  Conditions Governing Access
  Series VI has not yet been processed and is currently restricted from access.
  Series VI is currently unprocessed. Based on legacy inventories, this series contains nearly complete runs of womenSports (1974-1984), Women's Sports Magazine (1979-1984), and Women's Sports and Fitness (1984-1998). WSF is the official repository of Women's Sports and Fitness and its precursors. There is significant duplication of magazine issues. Also included are miscellaneous issues of Sports Illustrated, Sports Illustrated for Women, The International Swimmer, and Olympic Review. Material dates from 1974-2000.
- Series VII. Audiovisual and digital formats [RESTRICTED/ unprocessed], circa 1975-2012; 149 Linear feet in 149 record cartons
  Series VII has not yet been processed and is currently restricted from access.
  Series VII is currently unprocessed. This series contains audiovisual and digital format materials created by and collected by the WSF. According to legacy inventories, content includes athlete interviews, publicity and marketing material, and events footage. Formats include Betacam, U-matic, floppy disc, VHS, DVCPRO, CD, DVD, and zip disc. Materials date from approximately 1975-2012.
- Series VIII. Artifacts [RESTRICTED/ unprocessed], circa 1975-2010; 61 Linear feet in 61 record cartons
  Series VIII has not yet been processed and is currently restricted from access.
  Series VIII is currently unprocessed. This series contains artifacts, objects, and memorabilia created by and collected by WSF that have not been selected for accession into the New-York Historical Society Museum. This series may also contain large-format printed material, such as posters. The materials and objects date from approximately 1975-2010.
- Series IX. WSF Library [RESTRICTED/ unprocessed], 1957-2007; 135 Linear feet in 135 record cartons
  Series IX has not yet been processed and is currently restricted from access.
  Series IX. is currently unprocessed. This series contains the WSF's library collection of books and reference files originally collected and maintained in the WSF offices for staff and research use. Reference files are comprised primarily of an alphabetical reference file containing sports news article clippings. The WSF library contains books on women's sports and recreation. Material dates from 1957 to 2004.
  Subseries IX.A. Reference files and inventories
  Subseries IX.B. WSF library books
  - Subseries IX.A. Reference files and inventories [RESTRICTED/ unprocessed], 1975-2004; 8 Linear feet in 8 record cartons
    Series IX.A has not yet been processed and is currently restricted from access.
    Subseries IX.A. is currently unprocessed. According to legacy inventories, this series contains a group of reference files organized alphabetically by sport that contain reference material about individual sports, including athletes, history, organizations, and teams, mostly as news article clippings. The subseries also contain video inventories and research reports compiled by the WSF for reference use of their collections. Material dates from 1975 to 2004.
  - Subseries IX.B. WSF library books [RESTRICTED/ unprocessed], 1957-2007; 127 Linear feet in 127 record cartons
    Series IX.B has not yet been processed and is currently restricted from access.
    Subseries IX.B. is currently unprocessed. This subseres contains all books from the WSF's library collection, maintained in their offices for reference use and documentation of women's sports. Topics of books include general women's sports, athletes, and recreation. Books date from 1957 to 2007.